Okay, so now you've
got that data, it's
time to ask what
the heck does it
actually mean and how
do we learn a
lesson from it? Because
without a clear lesson,
those numbers are just
numbers and you can't
grow on just numbers
alone. So all the
benchmarks I'm about to
talk you through are
in the video planner
in the learner lesson
section. There's a big
checklist in there too
if it's going to
help. If you're using
RevTrack, some of the
data we're going to
go through will have
been pulled together nicely
on a dashboard, but
you can follow this
if you don't have
it too. It's just
going to take a
little bit more manual
tracking and the data
is not going to
be as clean. All
right, so the first
thing you do to
learn a lesson is
you start on step
one and you ask,
did I hit my
goal? The goal you
set every time you
plan the video, views,
sales or emails. The
answer is no, we
try and find out
why. If the answer
is yes, we try
and find out why.
That's it. Then step
two, we go to
the video lesson checklist
to try and work
out why that video
did what it did.
Problem is, look how
flipping big it is.
Tons of things, right?
And that's the thing
that sucks about YouTube.
This is how many
bottlenecks you can come
up against versus this
in your marketing and
this in your sales
system. It's weird. It's
way more complex and
it's way harder to
learn a lesson. So
what I'm going to
do now is just
break down the four
biggest places that most
of the mistakes or
reasons for success happen.
And they are positioning,
packaging, scripting and execution.
So let's start by
breaking down positioning. So
if your views are
lower than you expect,
say you're an eight
or 10 or worse,
basically what happens is
your fans and your
return viewers didn't click.
They didn't come back.
And that's often because
the topic or the
format left what they
expected, from you. And
this is what sucks
about YouTube because it's
very hard to tell
that you have left
that sometimes. Another reason
this might happen to
you is because you
are just solving too
many problems for too
many types of people
on your channel. So
here's what you want
to do when a
video flops. Drop your
thumbnail and your title
into guardrails and just
ask, why did this
flop? And then it's
going to give you
some lessons based on
the brain that you
filled out and the
way that you want
to position your channel.
That in itself might
then give you the
lesson that you can
add to this sheet.
Now, if it scored,
a one to four
out of 10 usually
means it's taken with
your existing viewers and
it's potentially grown with
a new audience too.
So you've got faster
views on release and
we want to find
out why. So we
can throw it into
guardrails and ask, why
did this video perform?
And it's going to
tell us. And then
you want to go
through the video checklist
too, to establish at
least one lesson as
to why. But what
I would do every
time is just remake
that video in a
slightly different way. So
repeat the format, very
similar title, very similar
thumbnail. And that can
be your lesson that
you try. If you
land in a video
that you've done before,
you're going to have
to do a little
bit of a different
thing. So you want
to go back and
look at the five
to six out of
10. It's much harder
to learn a lesson
from. It basically means
you probably didn't grow
with a cold audience.
You brought some viewers
back, but you maybe
didn't bring a huge
amount of them back.
So in terms of
positioning, you might want
to look at it
and ask, was this
a topic they really
care about? Now, the
next biggest criminal here
is packaging. It's basically
your thumbnail and your
title and your format.
So look, forget click
through rates. Just think
of this on a
human level, not an
algorithm level. It's too
hard to interpret. So
I think of it
like this. If the
views are low, did
you make the wrong
video format for your
fans and your return
viewers? A style of
video they're not used
to you making and
are not interested in?
Or did your thumbnail
and title lack the
how, what, and why
curiosity? And then the
third thing is, is
the design just amateur
cluttered or breaking the
design rules? 90 %
of the time when
a video doesn't perform,
it's going to be
the positioning or these
thumbnails. Now, if your
video exceeded expectation, all
you do is you
mark the thumbnail and
title and that style
to reuse as well
as the format. And
you can also ask
gardener, why did it
perform to try and
learn a little bit
about it too. Now,
the third thing that
causes a lot of
the problems is scripting.
So if you look
at your video and
you're like, do you
know what? The positioning
is good. The packaging
is good. This is
exactly what my viewers
usually want. It's usually
a sign that you
missed the mark with
your script. So one
thing you can check
is, is your average
watch time down, which
you can find out
here when the video
is being displayed. Now
keep in mind, if
your video is shorter,
it's going to be
down. That's just how
it works. So don't
just look at that
number and go, oh
no, it's down. That's
bad. Usually if positioning
and packaging is hitting
the mark, it basically
means your script has
confused people, didn't match
their expectations, didn't exceed
it, didn't give them
information that felt new,
easier, inspiring. So that's
the next thing you
want to look at.
So what I would
do is I would
take your script, put
it into point bot
and say, why did
this script not perform?
And it's going to
give you up to
10 issues, 10 lessons
you could learn. And
you can go through
and when one sticks
out, that can be
your lesson. And then
the fourth problem is
execution. So if everything
else is really good,
if your script's good,
if thumbnail and title
is good, you position
it, you can go
through and then you
can go through and
then you can go
through and positioning is
good, but your delivery
is flat or you're
nervous or you're too
fast. This is going
to be it most
of the time. And
the thing about this
is the only way
you can fix it
is just by practicing.
So the more you
present, the better your
pacing, the better your
energy, the better your
edits, the more confidence
you have, the more
your results are going
to increase. Now, AI
can't help you to
diagnose this yet. So
if you look at
all of those things
and you think they
all worked well, this
could potentially be the
unfortunate issue staring you
in the face. Okay.
So then once we've
done the metrics for
the videos and we've
tried to learn a
lesson, we go over.
To look at the
business metrics. So if
your goal was sales
from the video, RevTrack's
going to show you
the click -through rate
and the conversion rate
on the sales page
and the benchmarks that
we use to learn
from here to work
out if that was
good or bad are
5 % click -through
rate. That's a rocket
repeat, whatever you did,
a three to 5
% click -through rate.
That's excellent. Just repeat
exactly a one to
2 % click -through
rate is still above
average. So here you
want to check if
the call to action
was early enough or
came after some value.
And was relevant and
then below 1 %
click -through rate. This
is actually the industry
average. What you want
to try and do
is add in maybe
another call to action
and make sure your
call to action is
very tightly aligned with
the content of the
video. If I'm talking
to you about how
to write a script,
and then I do
a call to action
for a thumbnail product,
that's not in line.
So you're going to
see your click rates
drop and also make
sure your links at
the top of description
and the top comment.
And if you're below
a 0 .5 click
-through rate, that needs
some immediate action, but
it basically means people
aren't interested in what
you're trying to sell
them. So you need
to ask. Why for
the same reasons as
before. Now, when it
comes to sales page
conversions, you need to
realize this. So RevTrack
is going to show
you data. That's going
to show you the
sales page conversion rate
of that particular video.
But we don't want
to go making changes
to our sales page
based on this individual
number, because what can
happen is I can
make a video. It's
really in line with
my offer, nail the
call to action and
warm people up so
much. They click on
the sales page and
more people buy, or
I can do a
worse job. And that
same sales page could
not perform based on
what I did and
said in the video.
So we make all
of our decisions about
updating our sales page
based on the information
I'll teach you in
phase seven. And then
we want to look
at the click -through
rate and conversion from
our email or our
lead magnet. So once
the data is loaded
on day seven, you
can look and if
you've got an 8
% or above click
-through rate on that,
that's unbelievably good. Repeat
whatever you did. Your
lesson is just repeat
above 5%. We're still
excellent. Three to 5
% above average. Still
keep going. So 3
% that's the industry
average. You want to
move your click -through
rate earlier. You want
to make sure you
mentioned it multiple times
in the video that
they can sign up.
You want to make
sure your call to
action is very in
line with that lead
magnet. And then if
it's below 1%, you
got to fix that.
And it's the same
for the email signup
page as the sales
page. Don't make changes
based on this data,
the individual conversion rate
from a video, because
that can go up
and down a lot.
We make changes based
on what I teach
in phase seven. Okay.
So you're going to
see down the video
here at the bottom,
the lessons checklists, all
the benchmarks are on
it. It's going to
help you ask questions
that help you establish
things too. Now what
you need to go
and do is batch
produce your next three
to four videos, following
the system, start testing
new formats, repeating what
works, drive some traffic
into your system. That's
had some minor adjustments.
The goal of the
first three to four
videos is just to
make sure the minor
adjustments did anything. Or
if we need to
do more heavy lifting
and rebuilds of our
sales system after, which
for many of you,
the answer is going
to be yes, but
it doesn't make sense
to do the hard
work. The simple work
might work first, right?
Once you've made these
videos, move on to
phase seven, where you're
going to learn how
to measure your entire
business pipeline from YouTube
to actually people signing
up. And then we're
going to work out
what your next 10
X move and thing
to work is on
from that point.